Hello everyone, this video is for you to explain how to make a self-designed cloth zipper
First of all, we open the window of the drawer
Insert, we need to make a OBJ component of the zipper
Then we find our zipper on the component side
Then find our zipper inside
Double click to open, we can see that there is an OBJ file
Find the zipper you want to use
Then double-click to add it to our window
Select the component type
Then the unit is default to mm
We adjust it to mm here
In this case, the entire zipper is 10 times the original size
It is useful for packaging
Then click OK
After adding it in, we close the window of the drawer first
Then see this zipper is now added in
You can see that the zipper is added in
It's in our 3D window
The position of the coordinate point
Then we have to self-define the zipper
The self-defining position
It is needed to be in the position of the zipper
To the position of the coordinate point
So that its self-defined position
Can be correctly added to the zipper
So we can align it first
It will be more convenient when it falls out
No need to adjust anymore
You can come down a little more
Leave some space for it here
You can see that now our entire zipper is lower than our ground
If we want to simulate a plate below the ground
We can use this simulation attribute of the 3D window
In the blank of the 3D window
Open the right arrow in the blank
Then click on this little triangle on the ground
Close this conflict
So we can simulate it normally on the ground
Then our component
You also need to pay attention
Need to freeze it
If it is frozen, it will not move in this position
For our zipper
If you want to change its size
We can also select the component in the object window
Then select this zipper after
In the position of the specifications in the attribute editor
To change its size
For example, I want it
The direction of the Y-axis becomes shorter
Then I unlock this fixed ratio
Then adjust it to a smaller value here
Then I put its position back again
So we can do this for the size of the zipper
Self-defined change
We now come to create a cloth plate on the zipper
Then first of all
We choose the shape tool
Then click in the 2D window
Then this width
It's a little bit narrower than the top of this zipper
Let's take a look at the width of this zipper
Is 60
So let's create a 40 here
Then set the height to 200
Click to confirm
Then in the 3D window
We move it through this positioning ball
To the position near our zipper
What I choose here is the positioning ball of the world coordinate
You can switch here at the coordinate
In this case
No matter which view we switch
The position of this coordinate will not change
Then we can look at it in a specific perspective
Put it in the same position
We are going to cut the dragon layer
The inside of the dragon layer is easy to put aside
In the 3D window
Divide it into two parts
Then we switch to the editor sewing line tool
We only keep the sewing line of the upper and lower ends
Then change the particle diameter of the sheet to 5
The conflict thickness is changed to 1
Then turn on the simulation
You can see that this sheet is divided into two parts
You can see that this sheet is naturally simulated on the sheet
Now I need to make it more flat
That can be in this position
For example, add a sewing line here
We click on the 3D window
There is a small blue dot here
Then we go to create an internal multidirectional line
Near the small blue dot
Then create a sewing line
Let's sew up
We also add a sewing line here
Select our editor sheet tool
Click on the Z key
Then right-click to add to the outside of the sheet
Cut this line
We use the sewing line tool directly
Sew this section together with this section
After sewing
Remember to change these two sewing lines to overlays
Simulate again
That's it
If we need to edit this sheet
For example, I can stretch it a little longer at the bottom
Stretch another 3mm
After simulation, we find that there is a conflict in the sheet
Return to the simulation
Change to the texture surface display
Then this sheet should be in front of this sheet
Then we can use the setting layer tool
Set layers for two sheets
Just simulate it
Then we move this corner up a little
Move 20
Make a diagonal angle design
After the sheet adjustment number
Can apply the fabric
Then we are in the library window
Find the fabric
I want to use a piece of fabric here
We can search for it
Directly drag the desired fabric to the original fabric
Cover add
Let it have texture
Then simulate
This piece of fabric will be stiffer
At this time, switch to the thick texture surface to see
Then we can add another sticker on top
We go to choose a sticker we want to add
Right-click to add as a sticker
Then put it on our 2D window panel
Add it to the small panel
This sticker is a bit big
We can shrink it a bit
That's about it
After this is done
We will export this pull out as an OBJ
File export OBJ
Find the file holder
Name save
When saving
We pay attention to the export options
Choose all the panels and stickers and accessories
Then multiple targets
Then compare here
Then in this proportion
We just used this centimeter
This side is also a unit unit with centimeters
Then here we choose to save with the file
Save as zip
This can not be hooked
The following three are not hooked
Just hook this one
Click to confirm
After confirmation
We come to the file holder
Find this zip file just saved
This is the zip file
We will decompress it
This is the file holder that we decompress
In this
Now we have a file
Save
Save the project file
If there is a follow-up change
Can also be changed on the original file
We see here
If the file holder
maison
Then it won't show this
copy
This is the file holder
Exposed to the back side
We should also성
For the ratio, we still choose cm, pay attention here
If it is still 100% poured in, this slice will be very large
We should adjust it to 10%
Because we originally from mm to cm, it is 10 times magnified
Now we are returning from mm to mm
So it should be 10% of the original
Then this OBJ
Let's click on this browser button
Find this OBJ that does not bring slices
Click open
You can see that it is in the preview window below us
You can preview 360 degrees
Click OK
Then we will do this preset
After doing it, we now open a costume with a 3D zipper
Let's apply this slice
Then we find the position of this slice on our costume
We see this little triangle at the bottom
Click this
It's what we just did
We can change it
We can see that it is now on our clothes
If we want to edit its material
It is also possible
Select the corresponding object to edit
The first click is to select the entire head of the zipper and the mouth
The second click is to select our zipper
There are different elements on the zipper
Then we can set them separately
For example, I want to set our cloth bag
Click this cloth bag
The cloth bag above
If I want to edit this sticker of mine
Click the position of the sticker
You can replace it with other texture pictures
But this texture picture
Everyone needs to pay attention to its ratio and position
It is locked here
So if you use other pictures to replace it
There may be some deformations
But you can replace the color
For example, I changed this hole to another color
Then edit without texture
We can also replace it
And this texture picture
If you think it needs to be adjusted to this ratio now
You can change it again and adjust this ratio
Enlarge it 10 times and change it to 11
You can see that this ratio is changed
Of course, we also have to put our texture picture
This ratio is also adjusted to 11
So it's right
Then you can see the zipper we have now
Select again
You can make the strength of this texture picture
You can make it a little bigger
To increase the texture of the text
The ratio here is 11% a little too big
Adjust to 5
And if you want to add a layer to this layer
Or to make another layer
It is important to adjust the height of the texture picture
You can choose this layer
And then go to the top
It is important to save
Select this file
You can see the drawer where you want to save
For example
What I want to save is this layer
Click OK
I will switch it back to another type of puller
Then you can open it here
Find the puller we just saved
You can see that it is the puller just saved
The above is our custom puller